Hi again. In this program, we've
discussed that when you're
managing a project,
you always have to consider
the triple constraint:
time, scope, and budget.
Each of these three elements
will impact the project,
and if any one of them suffers,
the overall quality of
the project suffers too.
There's an important distinction
between "quality" and "done."
Simply finishing a
project isn't enough;
the project must meet the
customer's standards of
quality, rather than
just be completed.
Like all things in
project management,
the more effectively you
communicate with your team,
the more likely your team
will produce high-quality
deliverables.
How do we define quality in
a project management sense?
Quality is when you fulfill
the outlined requirements for
the deliverable
and meet or exceed
the needs or expectations
of your customers.
When it comes to quality,
it's important to
deliver a product or
service that meets
your customer's needs.
To meet their needs,
you have to know
important quality
management concepts and
oversee the implementation of
a project management
quality plan.
To set yourself up for success,
you should consider
the four main concepts
of quality management,
which are: quality standards,
quality planning, quality
assurance, and quality control.
The quality process begins
with setting quality standards.
Quality standards provide
requirements, specifications,
or guidelines that can be
used to ensure that products,
processes, or services are
fit for achieving
the desired outcome.
Set quality standards
with your team and
your customer at the
beginning of your project.
Take the time to define
the quality standards and
criteria for your current work
so that your team
members and stakeholders
understand exactly what they are.
After you set those
well-defined quality standards,
you'll want to check-in
periodically and make sure
everything looks okay and
the requirements are met.
Remember that well-defined
standards and
requirements lead to less
rework and schedule delays.
Let's put this in
an example using
the scenario we've been using
throughout the program.
You're a project manager
at Office Green,
a company that specializes in
plant decor for offices
and other businesses,
and you're leading a
project called Plant Pals,
a new service that will provide
top clients with
desk-friendly plants.
Here's an example of a few
quality standards
for this project.
Reliability standards:
Each planter arrives by
the agreed-upon time
and in good condition,
ready to be placed at a desk.
The suppliers have enough
plants in their warehouses
to fulfill the customer
demand on time.
Usability standards:
Planters won't cause
customers allergic
reactions or illness
and will be suitable for
all people and
animals, if necessary.
Similarly, you may have
product standards:
The supplier should meet
your brand's look and feel,
use the specified materials,
and be delivered intact.
You should adhere to
quality standards
across all products
and processes.
For instance, you may have
usability standards
implemented in
the website development
process by stating
that the website must
be easy to navigate,
whether from a phone,
computer, or tablet.
Next step, quality planning.
Quality planning refers
specifically to the actions of
a project manager or
the team to establish
and conduct a process
for identifying and
determining exactly
which standards of
quality are in fact
relevant to the project as
a whole, and how to satisfy them.
To steer that discussion,
you can ask yourself,
"What outcome do my customers
want at the end of this project?
What does quality
look like for them?
How can I meet
their expectations?
How will I determine if
the quality measures will
lead to project success?"
This is where you'll
plan the procedures
to achieve the quality standards.
Recall that one of the Project
Plant Pals quality standards
is reliability,
the expectation that each plant
arrives on time and
in good condition.
So as a quality planning measure,
you'll need to make plans
with your plant provider to test
the durability of your planters
before you decide to use them.
The third concept of
quality management is
quality assurance.
Quality assurance,
often shortened to QA,
is all about evaluating
if your project is moving
towards delivering a high-quality
service or product.
Unlike quality standards
and quality planning,
QA spans the whole
project life cycle,
rather than taking place
at a specific phase.
Your quality plan should
include regular audits to confirm
that everything is
going to plan and
the necessary procedures
are being followed.
Regular check-ins and
reporting to stakeholders will
help boost their confidence,
and yours, along the way.
Quality assurance is where
you'll make sure that you and
your clients are getting
the exact product
you contracted for.
So with Project Plant Pals,
this is where your team
will inspect options for
planters and perhaps sit in
on the durability testing.
If you make plans for
your plant provider to
handle the durability
testing on their own,
make sure you are tracking
their progress and
checking in regularly.
The final concept of
quality management
is quality control,
often shortened to QC.
Here, techniques are used in
order to ensure
quality standards when
a problem is identified, or if
the quality plan is not
executed in the desired manner
and corrective actions
should be affected.
Quality control involves
monitoring project results and
delivery to determine
if they are
meeting desired results or not.
If not, then alternative
actions should be taken.
Quality control is
also integral to
creating a more successful
landing for the next project.
After the plants are placed
throughout the
customers' offices,
quality control may
look like you or
your team member taking a final
walk-through of the offices
where the plants were delivered.
You'd be checking for things like
broken planters or plants
that were damaged in transit
and swapping them
out when necessary.
You may not do this
for every customer,
but it's a good idea to do it
as you're starting
out in case you
spot issues to improve
upon when you're
back in the office.
If you stuck to
your quality plan,
checking on quality throughout
the life cycle of your project
(QA), and of course
correcting as needed (QC),
the likelihood of meeting
your quality standards is
high, resulting in a
high-quality deliverable at
the end of your
project that satisfies
your organizational goals and
exceeds the customer's
expectations.
And there you have it—quality
management!
Great! So now we've learned
more about how to
identify and explain the
concept of quality management,
which includes quality standards,
quality planning, quality
assurance, and quality control.
In the next video,
we'll discuss how
to use soft skills,
like negotiating and
practicing empathy, to meet
customers' needs in terms
of quality. Meet you there!